 <doc>
  <float name="score">2.9402447</float>
  <arr name="applicant"><str>Numerous</str></arr>
  <arr name="applicant_sort"><str>Numerous</str></arr>
  <arr name="author"><str>Various</str></arr>
  <arr name="author_sort"><str>Various</str></arr>
  <arr name="brief"><bool>false</bool></arr>
  <arr name="dateRcpt"><date>2014-07-16T04:00:00Z</date></arr>
  <arr name="disseminated"><date>2014-07-29T16:21:59.933Z</date></arr>
  <arr name="exParte"><bool>false</bool></arr>
  <arr name="fileNumber"><str>35 emails</str></arr>
  <arr name="id"><long>6018247774</long></arr>
  <arr name="modified"><date>2014-07-30T18:10:01.856Z</date></arr>
  <arr name="pages"><int>20</int></arr>
  <arr name="proceeding"><str>14-28</str></arr>
  <arr name="regFlexAnalysis"><bool>false</bool></arr>
  <arr name="reportNumber"><str>263 Total emails</str></arr>
  <arr name="smallBusinessImpact"><bool>false</bool></arr>
  <arr name="submissionType"><str>LETTER</str></arr>
  <arr name="text"><str>The attached document is part of a mass mailing. The number of 
identical documents as specified in the File Number/City, St. field 
have been received by the Commission on this same date. You may 
view the documents at the FCC Reference Information Center, at 445 
12th Street, SW, Washington, DC, Room CY-A257. 


As an Internet user who believes strongly in the importance of a free and 
open I nternet, I urge the FCC to reclassify broadband Internet access as 
a telecommunications service, and save Net Neutrality. 
In addition, the FCC should reject the proposed rules that would allow 
Internet service providers to divide the Internet into fast lanes for 
wealthy corporations and slow lanes for the rest of us. 
---------------------------- Email 9,682 ----------------------------
From: 
To: 
Date: 
Subject: 
xxxxxxxx 
xxxxxxxx 
07/16/2014 01:13 AM 
Fast lanes, broadband &amp; Title II Common Carriers 
1) Should fast lanes be banned? YES 
2) Should broadband providers be classified as Title II Common Carriers? 
YES 
3) Should these same rules apply to wireless (mobile) providers? YES 
By allowing ISPs to charge a premium for preferential treatment (which is 
exactly what this will become) the US government will effectively stifle 
one of the few industries we still dominate on a global scale, by 
crushing innovation and the entrepreneurial spirit of this nation. 
The free market is unable to respond accordingly given the 
anticompetitive laws restricting carriers to cover certain geographic 
locations. With laws that led carriers to enjoy essentially monopolies in 
many areas around the nation, consumers have lost the ability to be 
protected from price gouging and corporate market manipulation. In 
addition, smaller companies will no longer be able to compete . There 
would be no Facebooks, Linked-Ins, Googles, or Netflixes. 
Thank you for adding my concerns to those against the FCCs currently 
proposed plans. 

R. Wilson 
1425 Broadway #126 
Seattle, WA 98122 
206-290-8789 
---------- ------ ------------ Email 9,683 ----------------------------
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:13 AM 
Subject: Comment Re: WC Docket No. 14-28 
As an Internet user who believes strongly in the importance of a free and 
open Internet, I urge the FCC to reclassify broadband Internet access as 
a telecommunications service, and save Net Neutrality. 
In addition, the FCC should reject the proposed rules that would allow 
Internet service providers to divide the Internet into fast lanes for 
wealthy corporations and slow lanes for the rest of us. 
Adam Eberhardt 
3239 Hyde St 
Oakland, CA 94601 
&lt;http://list.credoaction.com/wf/open?upn=CFwW2LiM8egNfpSWPK172vcklJm5Gzqa 
Ow5Fuc04BSI6ZDzoiuuLfXaGop06WlI1EltNtdVyNAzqelCzDr7jAdglBipdtVxQCrGJwVJJF 
QBup65n8Sl33nU03ee4qxqPVOBrzSLllalmmAHxmqdDbgSIOibOU-
2B09bxdjLtYtSavYj lkil-2F7MQ4Pqrw9CE3ihhFU8Iuf57cOBSgI6bx4BXQ-3D-3D&gt; 
---------------------------- Email 9,684 ------------------------ --- -
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:13 AM 
Subject: Public Comment 
We already told what to do about net neutrality once before when you (the 
FCC) had hearings on this a couple years back in 2010. 
An overwhelming Majority of Public Comments told you to reclassify it. 
You didnt listen and here we are 4 years later making the same exact case 
because the court overruled your error . 
You will never listen to ordinary people. 
Cause you don't care about them. 
And no matter how many comments flood your input in support of 
reclassification you surely wont do it. 
I'm guessing Mr Wheeler will surely look to serve his Former Corporation 
over his Country. 
Reclassify Now and quit kicking the can down the road for a Republican to 
get the blame for killing the internet. 
Jamie Onint 

-- - ------------ - - - ---- -- - - - - Email 9,685 - -- - --- - --------------------
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:13 AM 
Subject: Docket number: 14-28 protecting an open internet 
To Chairman Tom Wheeler and the FCC Commissioners- ---
Chairman Wheeler, 
It is critical to free speech and the development of new businesses that 
Internet Service Providers not be allowed to regulate Internet data 
rates. 
The modern use of the Internet was based on the idea that anyone could 
put up a web page or otherwise communicate with anyone else, anywhere in 
the world regardless of how much money they had. I know. My use of the 
Internet goes back to the command line days. The current equivalent of 
the early web page is streaming media precisely what the large ISPs 
want to throttle. The egalitarianism of free speech on the Internet 
would be stifled. 
Similarly, with regard to nascent businesses, the Internet has 
traditionally offered a platform for even the smallest start up to reach 
customers . Demanding premium charges to permit unthrottled streaming 
media, VOIP, video conferencing and other bandwidth-intensive 
technologies to function is an egregious and unreasonable and unfair 
burden for smaller businesses. 
I hope you will heed the will of everyone other than large ISPs and 
support Net Neutrality. 
Sincerely, 
Eric Nathanson 
Eric Nathanson 
91324 
------------- - -- - ------ - - - -- Email 9,686 ------- - --------------------
From: 
To: 
Date: 
Subject: 
xxxxxxxx 
xxxxxxxx 
07/16/2014 01:13 AM 
Docket number: 14-28 protecting an open internet 
To Chairman Tom Wheeler and the FCC Commissioners----
Dear Sirs, 

I am a musician in training. I take lessons on my computer each week . 
Also, I use video resources to further my knowledge about music theory 
and practice. Without an open and free internet this would be expensive 
and prohibitive for me. 
Along with this I read newspaper articles on line and watch video feeds. 
Currently much of this is free. Since I live on a limited budget any 
increase in cost wil l have a detrimental impact upon me. 
In my opinion, a free and open internet is a necessity and we should not 
allow a few corporations to l i mit access by manipul ating this 
resource via pay to play schemes . 
Terence Brownlow 
94901 
------ - ------ ------- ----- -- - Email 9,687 --- - -- ------ - - -- - -----------
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:13 AM 
Subject: Docket number: 14 - 28 protecting an open internet 
To Chairman Tom Wheeler and the FCC Commissioners----
No Content Found -- Please specify some content 
Jink Huge 
91362 
------------------- --------- Email 9,688 -------- ---- - --- -- --- - - - - - - -
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:14 AM 
Subject: Strongly in Favor of Net Neutrality, Strongly Opposed to the 
Prioritization of Certain Favored Internet Services 
I strongly favor net neutrality and am strongly opposed to any 
regulation or legislation that allows for the prioritization of one 
type of Internet service over another . The engine of Internet 
innovation is completely dependent on the equal treatment of all 
traffic. If you take that away the Internet will cease to create new 
industries, jobs, and new innovative services and become a stagnant, 
mediocre, commercial channel controlled by a few rich companies. 
Innovation will be driven off shore and foreign economies will enjoy 
its benefits . 
-- Morri s Creeger 
Portola Valley, CA 94028 
- -- ------- --- ----- - - -------- Email 9,689 -- ----------- ------ - ------- -

From: namastepj®me.com 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:14 AM 
Subject: GN Docket No. 14-28. Protect net neutrality, reclassify 
broadband access. 
To Whomever it May Concern: 
Protect net neutrality, and do it right this time. 
Recognize the reality that broadband Internet service is a 
telecommunications service, not an "information service," as it is 
currently misclassified. It should be regulated under Title II as a 
common carrier, subject to all the nondiscrimination principles that 
govern such utilities. 
Statements from your chairman make it clear that reclassifying Internet 
service in this way may be necessary to ensure net neutrality in the 
future. The currently-proposed, weaker rules will allow ISPs to 
discriminate against minority voices, smaller companies, and diverse 
sources of information. Ensure that this does not happen by issuing 
strong common-carrier regulations now, covering both wired and wireless 
broadband carriers. 
Protect the rights of minorities, small businesses, and consumers. 
Protect net neutrality now. 
Ms Paige Harrison, R.N., BSN, OCN 
New York, NY 10024 
us 
-------------------- -------- Email 9,690 -------------------- --------
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:14 AM 
Subject: Docket number: 14-28 protecting an open internet 
To Chairman Tom Wheeler and the FCC Commissioners----
Net Neutrality the last real outpost of a free society. We need Net 
Neutrality to retain that ideal of America, of a free country where 
everyone can express their opinion, have their say and seek out the 
information they need. We are not ruled by corporations, not yet, not 
completely, please leave this one last freedom available to the American 
people. Protect Net Neutrality- make laws to protect it. Protect an open 
internet; this is one of the most important civil right issues of our 
time. Do the right thing. 
Andrea Patt 
95503 

------------- ----- ---------- Email 9,691 ---------- ---- - --- ----- ---- -
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:15 AM 
Subject: Net neutrality 
Is the FCC for consumers or Corporations? In case it's not clear at the 
point, the people want net neutrality. 
Steve Hansen, Granite Bay, ca. 
--------------- ---- --------- Email 9,692 ---- - ------ --------- --------
From: 
To: 
Date: 
Subject: 
kk khan 
xxxxxxxx 
xxxxxxxx 
07/16 / 2014 01:15 AM 
Tell the FCC to protect a free and open Internet 
123 Nunya 
Buffalo, NY 14223 
July 16, 2014 
Tom Wheeler 
Dear Tom Wheel er: 
These comments are in response to proceeding #14-28. 
Free speech should not be bought and sold. The proposal to grant ISPs the 
right to charge for •fast lanes' threatens this celebrated American 
principle. The company that connects us to the internet should not get to 
manipulate or control what we do on the internet. 
I'm calling on you to reclassify the Internet as a telecommunications 
service to obligate ISPs to del i ver all data on the Internet without 
discrimination. Please do the right thing: let corporati ons know that the 
Internet is not for sale to the highest bidder. 
Thank you for preserving a free and open Internet. 
Sincerely, 
kk khan 
------------ ---- ------- ----- Email 9,693 - ---- - ------------- - - - ------

From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:15 AM 
Subject: Tell the FCC to protect a free and open Internet 
Donald Ludwig 
19550 Grayhawk Dr. #1053 
Scottsdale, AZ 85255-3984 
July 16, 2014 
Tom Wheeler 
Dear Tom Wheeler: 
These comments are in response to proceeding #14-28. 
Free speech should not be bought and sold. The proposal to grant ISPs the 
right to charge for 'fast lanes' threatens this celebrated American 
principle. The company that connects us to the internet should not get to 
manipulate or control what we do on the internet. 
I'm calling on you to reclassify the Internet as a telecommunications 
service to obligate ISPs to deliver all data on the Internet without 
discrimination. Please do the right thing: let corporations know that the 
Internet is not for sale to the highest bidder. 
Thank you for preserving a free and open Internet. 
Sincerely, 
Donald Ludwig 
(760) 219-8124 
---------------------------- Email 9,694 ----------------------------
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:15 AM 
Subject: Tell the FCC to protect a free and open Internet 
brianna onken 
409 NW Tork Pl 
Hillsboro, OR 97006-2796 
July 16, 2014 
Tom Wheeler 

-------------- ---------------------··----- ·-·--- .. -.. , . . .... ...... . 
Dear Tom Wheeler: 
These comments are in response to proceeding #14-28. 
Free speech shoul d not be bought and sold . The proposal to grant ISPs the 
right to charge for 'fast lanes' threatens this celebrated American 
principle. The company that connects us to the internet should not get to 
manipulate or control what we do on the internet. 
I'm calling on you to reclassify the Internet as a telecommunications 
service to obligate ISPs to deliver all data on the Internet withou t. 
discrimination. Please do the right thing: let corporations know that the 
Internet is not for sale to the highest bidder. 
Thank you for preserving a free and open Internet. 
Sincerely, 
brianna onken 
---------- ------- ----------- Email 9,695 ---------- --- --- -- ------ -- --
From: 
To: 
Date: 
Subject: 
xxxxxxxx 
xxxxxxxx 
07/16 / 2014 01:15 AM 
Tell the FCC to protect a free and open Internet 
Peter Sommers 
2393 Filbert Street 
San Francisco, CA 94123 - 3313 
July 16, 2014 
Tom Wheeler 
Dear Tom Wheeler: 
These comments are in response to proceeding #14 - 28. 
Free speech should not be bought and sold. The proposal to grant ISPs the 
right to charge for •fast lanes' threatens this celebrated American 
principle. The company that connects us to the internet should not get to 
manipulate or control what we do on the internet. 
I'm calling on you to reclassify the Internet as a telecommunications 
service to obligate ISPs to deliver all data on the Internet without 

discrimination. Please do the right thing: let corporations know that the 
Internet is not for sale to the highest bidder. 
Thank you for preserving a free and open Internet. 
Sincerely, 
Peter Sommers 
415 -929-8111 
--------------------- - - -- --- Email 9,696 ------------------------ --- -
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:15 AM 
Subject: Tell the FCC to protect a free and open Internet 
George Wheeler-Brownlee 
4131 E Glenn Street 
Tucson, AZ 85712-1534 
July 16, 2014 
Tom Wheeler 
Dear Tom Wheeler: 
These comments are in response to proceeding #14-28. 
Free speech should not be bought and sold. The proposal to grant ISPs the 
right to charge for 'fast lanes' threatens this celebrated American 
principle. The company that connects us to the internet should not get to 
manipulate or control what we do on the internet. 
I'm calling on you to reclassify the Internet as a telecommunications 
service to obligate ISPs to deliver all data on the Internet without 
discrimination. Please do the right thing: let corporations know that the 
Internet is not for sale to the highest bidder. 
Thank you for preserving a free and open Internet. 
Sincerely, 
George Wheeler-Brownlee 
5203270834 

---------------------------- Email 9,697 ----------------------- - ----
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:15 AM 
Subject: Tell the FCC to protect a free and open Internet 
Gordon Gerrish 
56850 fishhatchery road 
St Ignatius, MT 59865-9216 
July 16, 2014 
Tom Wheeler 
Dear Tom Wheeler: 
These comments are in response to proceeding #14-28. 
Free speech s hould not b e bought and sold. The proposal to grant I SPs the 
right to charge for 'fast lanes' threatens this celebrated America n 
principle. The company that connects us to the internet should not get to 
manipulate or control what we do on the internet. 
I'm calling on you to reclassify the Internet as a telecommunications 
service to obligate ISPs to deliver all data on t he I n ternet withou t 
d iscrimination. Please do t he right thing: let corporations know that the 
Internet is not for sale t o the highest bidder. 
Thank you for preserving a free and open Internet. 
Sincerely, 
Gordon Gerrish 
---------------------------- Email 9,698 ----------------------------
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: Op xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:15 AM 
Subject: Tell the FCC to protect a fre e and open Internet 
Scott Jennings 
2519 Palmer Ave 
New Orleans, LA 70118-63 19 
July 16, 2014 
Tom Wheeler 

Dear Tom Wheeler: 
These comments are in response to proceeding #14-28. 
Free speech should not be bought and sold. The proposal to grant ISPs the 
right to charge for 'fast lanes' threatens this celebrated American 
principle. The company that connects us to the internet should not get to 
manipulate or control what we do on the internet. 
I'm calling on you to reclassify the Internet as a telecommunications 
service to obligate ISPs to deliver all data on the Internet without 
discrimination. Please do the right thing: let corporations know that the 
Internet is not for sale to the highest bidder. 
Thank you for preserving a free and open Internet. 
Sincerely, 
Scott Jennings 
3186550371 
- ------ - ------ -- ----------- - Email 9,699 - ------------- - ------------ -
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:15 AM 
Subject: Tell the FCC to protect a free and open Internet 
tammy huckabone 
1144 CR 12 
Pennellville, NY 13132 
July 16, 2014 
Tom Wheeler 
Dear Tom Wheeler: 
These comments are in response to proceeding #14 - 28. 
Free speech should not be bought and sold. The proposal to grant ISPs the 
right to charge for 'fast lanes• threatens this celebrated American 
principle. The company that connects us to the internet should not get to 
manipulate or control what we do on the internet. 
I'm calling on you to reclassify the Internet as a telecommunications 

service to obligate ISPs to deliver all data on the Internet without 
discrimination. Please do the right thing: let corporations know that the 
Internet is not for sale to the highest bidder. 
Thank you for preserving a free and open Internet. 
A Please protect a free and open internet. 
Sincerely, 
tammy huckabone 
- ------- ---- - - ----- ---------Email 9,700 -------------- - - - -----------
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:16 AM 
Subject: Official Public Comment on Rules Regarding Net Neutrality 
My name is Andrea Dewees and I live in Seattle, WA. 
Net neutrality, the principle that Internet service providers (ISPs) 
treat all data that travels over their networks equally, is important to 
me because without it ISPs could have too much power to determine my 
Internet experience by providing better access to some services but not 
others. 
A pay--to-play Internet worries me because new, innovative services that 
can't afford expensive fees for better service will be less likely to 
succeed. 
The Internet is important to me because it is an essential commerce 
portal and information medium. Without net neutrality, the freedom of 
information sharing will be restricted at the hands of big business and 
the 1%. The FCC's current rulings regarding net neutrality are not in 
line with the intentions of a capitalist society requiring fair 
competition in the marketplace . Because of this , I feel that I may be 
unduly burdened as a user of the internet in that my access to 
information and innovative resources will be limited, funneled or 
restricted. 
Sincerely, 
Andrea Dewees 
8509 29th Ave NW 
Seattle, WA 98117 
--- ------- ------------------ Email 9,701 ---------------- -- ----------
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:16 AM 
Subject: 14-28 Protect net neutrality 
I support net neutrality. Please c l assify broadband and mobile providers 
as Title II Common Carriers, and ban the "fast lane". 

The internet has revolutionized our world. Net neutrality is vital to 
allow future innovations. 
Lora Swartzendruber 
1700 Pennsylvania 
Lawrence, KS 66044 
---------------------------- Email 9,702 - - - -------------------------
From: 
To: 
Date: 
Subject: 
xxxxxxxx 
xxxxxxxx 
07/16/2014 01:16 AM 
Docket number: 14-28 protecting an open internet 
To Chairman Tom Wheeler and the FCC Commissioners----
To those whose choices will so greatly impact the internet. I spent my 
post graduate studies searching libraries to understand classical and 
medieval cultures and history ... years. A relatively open internet has 
allowed me to search information much more quickly from various sources 
and countries to try to ascertain what is actually happening in the world 
today. That ability has been invaluable to my understanding of the world 
and the major players on its stage ... thing Shakespeare's" ... life's 
but a tale told by an idot, full of sound and fury, signifying 
nothing ... " Modern commercial media is like that. 
In order to avoid the violence and revolution that monetary control of 
the internet information source now available, we must have an open, 
neutral internet access policy. If not, we will sooner or later have the 
violence that supression of open iformation will generate. Why would you 
want that? 
Information control helped to formet world wars I &amp; II, not to mention 
the battles of Troy and the conflicts betweent the Greeks and Persians, 
not to mention so many others. Why would you want us to go down those 
paths again? 
Peter Vanderhoof 
98363 
----------- -- --- --- - ---- ---- Email 9,703 ---------------- -- - --- ------
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:16 AM 
Subject: Comment re: WC Docket No. 14-28 
As an Internet user who believes strongly in the importance of a free and 
open Internet, I urge the FCC to reclassify broadband Internet access as 
a telecommunications service, and save Net Neutrality. 

In addition, the FCC should reject the proposed rules that would allow 
Internet service providers to divide the Internet into fast lanes for 
wealthy corporations and slow lanes for the rest of us. 
-- -- -- - ---- -- ------ --- ------ Email 9,704 ---- -- ---- - - -- ------- - ----- -
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:16 AM 
Subject: Reclassify the Internet as a common carrier 
To: The Commissioners of the FCC 
Your proposed path would open the door to widespread discrimination 
online. It would give Internet service providers the green light to 
implement pay-for-priority schemes that would be a disaster for startups, 
nonprofits and everyday Internet users who cannot afford these 
unnecessary tolls. 
I urge you to scrap these proposed rules and instead restore the 
principl e of online nondiscrimination by reclassifying broadband as a 
telecommunications service. 
Javier Casanova 
ON LSA 2G8 
- - - - -- -- - --- -- ------- -- ----- Email 9,705 --- -- -- -- -- -- ----- -- ------ - -
From: 
To: 
Date: 
Subject: 
xxxxxxxx 
Op~xxxxxxxx 
07/16/2014 01:17 AM 
Docket number: 14 - 28 protecting an open internet 
To Chairman Tom Wheeler and the FCC Commissioners----
It is our right to freedom for the first amendment!! You have NO RIGHT 
to impede, decide or regulate our right to information, entertainment or 
any other internet service offered . Mind your own business!!! 
kk khan 
14223 
-- - -- -- ---- - -- - ---- - ------- - Email 9,706 ----- - ------- - -- - -- -- --- - -- -
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:17 AM 
Subject: Comment Re: WC Docket No. 14 - 28 
As an Internet user who believes strongly in the importance of a free and 
open Internet, I urge the FCC to reclassify broadband Internet access as 
a telecommunications service, and save Net Neutrality. 

In addition, the FCC should reject the proposed rules that would allow 
Internet service providers to divide the Internet into fast lanes for 
wealthy corporations and slow lanes for the rest of us. 
Amanda Bloom 
2950 International Blvd 
Oakland, CA 94601 
&lt;http://list.credoaction.com/wf/open?upn=CFwW2LiM8egNfp5WPK172vcklJm5Gzqa 
Ow5Fuc04B5I - 2FZI7pLgWaGecilGYw9uksyqFkDWx3cawS3uQTRgcqVvCksiq- 2FclQ-
2FkiAMBEjGYAFYBSOlsERC- 2FnBAmSgFrHA0-2BlFWvYdkLIJyLUlwqIJlx4nqFKyhS-
2Fh4GNaMbQvQKr202bMGLPLWoeSzCsGnN-2FeBG4v6yk-2FZU8pSzzzfnjPfIA- 3D- 3D&gt; 
---------------------- - ----- Email 9,707 - -- ---- -- ------------------ -
From: 
To: 
Date: 
xxxxxxxx 
xxxxxxxx 
07/16/2014 01:17 AM 
Subject: Docket number: 14 - 28 protecting an open internet 
To Chairman Tom Wheeler and the FCC Commissioners----
with our govt/new/info so bought and paid for that is meaningless and 
folks so mis/unimforrned, it's sad that ya'll even consider further 
commercializing the info hiway. 
Shame on you 
Elizabeth Patterson 
84115 
- - - --- - ------------------- - -Email 9,708 -------- --- - ----------- - ----
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:17 AM 
Subject: Comment Re: WC Docket No . 14 - 28 
As an Internet user who believes strongly in the importance of a free and 
open Internet, I urge the FCC to reclassify broadband Internet access as 
a telecommunications service, and save Net Neutrality. 
In addition, the FCC should reject the proposed rules that would allow 
Internet service providers to divide the Internet into fast lanes for 
wealthy corporations and slow lanes for the rest of us. 
L YOUNG 
2324 W Irving Pk #309 
Chicago, IL 60618 
&lt;http://list.credoaction.com/wf/open?upn=CFwW2LiM8egNfp5WPKl72vck1Jm5Gzqa 
Ow5Fuc04B5Kd6Dj4fQopYBaiv24QHQ4nzuusP8qSvUZDX9npmD96DdV83jqc7phMsaNGrVSOe 

E9k4ev-2FQd6KxvpkNZvObFY-2F40-2BgSJFmTqklMVHqCw-2B2UHQDEE-
2BLRK35vDruAxTVg-2BlEc8tTZ8RkhsFg6238xltXHxivQF8Q4ZyJoRv6DpyaNg-3D- 3D&gt; 
- ---- -- ---------- ----- - --- --Email 9,709 ---------------------- - - ----
From: 
To: 
Date: 
Subject: 
xxxxxxxx 
xxxxxxxx 
07/16/2014 01:17 AM 
Docket number: 14-28 protecting an open internet 
To Chairman Tom Wheeler and the FCC Commissioners----
I run a small business on the internet. I cannot afford to pay cable 
companies anytime someone views my website. This proposed action of yours 
in making the internet a sort of buffet for those browsing the internet 
will severely impact me. It will also impact small business owners such 
as myself. Leaving the internet "NET NEUTRAL" will allow those of us 
without the resources of a big company the chance to survive. 
Please do not put into place this draconian law into place. 
Sam Chetcuti 
94080 
---------------------- ------ Email 9,710 ------------- - -- - - - - - - - -----
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:18 AM 
Subject: Save the Internet for the people 
Chairman Wheeler, 
Please keep the internet as it is today. The internet is the last part 
of my life that is not one sided in favor for the BIG businesses. They 
are the ones who hold our internet lives in their hands, but their 
overwhelming greed, they want, with your help and blessing, to squeeze 
the last dollar out of the rest of the population. 
Just what is the reason you are in favor to make the change? 
of the very rich that want it, the rest of the country do not? 
seems you must side with the very rich? Is that it? 
There a few 
So it 
I was in the telephone industry when Judge Green handed down his verdict 
to level the playing field and allow competition to prevail. The price 
of telephone service dropped significantly, service greatly improved, and 
features and capabilities exploded. Now look what has happened, the 
telephone industry is coming back to where it was before the breakup of 
AT&amp;T. 
It is looking that, with your help, that the internet is going the same 
way, a few lording it over all the rest. What will be coming if this 
passes, is the AT&amp;T monopoly will coming back in the form of the 
internet. Look forward and you will see the damage this will do. It 

cannot improve the internet except i n the pocket of a few. Is there any 
way to stop, or at l east slow down the oligarchy? 
Jerry Sharp 
xxxxxxxx 
145 Trail Rider Way 
Georgetown TX 78633 
864 - 904-2868 c 
----------- - - -- ----------- - -Email 9,711 - - ---- - ---- - - - -- - - -- - - -- ----
From: 
To: 
Date: 
xxxxxxxx 
xxxxxxxx 
07/16/2014 01: 18 AM 
Subject: Comment Re: WC Docket No. 14-28 
As an Internet user who believes strongly in the importance of a free and 
open Internet, I urge the FCC to reclassify broadband Internet access as 
a telecommunications service, and save Net Neutrality . 
In addition, the FCC shoul d reject the proposed rules that would allow 
Internet service providers to divide the Internet into fast l anes for 
wealthy corporations and slow lanes for the rest of us. 
Bill R Taylor 
12400 Bakers Creek Rd. 
Redwood Valley, CA 95470 
&lt;http://list.credoaction.com/wf/open?upn=CFwW2LiM8egNfp5WPKl72vcklJm5Gzqa 
Ow5Fuc04B5LezjMuAZWvxknMKawhv-2BdlVOEOkIBCbHemyyHx2jDTvQWLDG-2BdkwCc -
2B9JSiGa50bsAPgEAbHltGEm5xR-2BLjNWrndwIHbgSbDBeUtUf5baS28KL-
2FKvMRKJaX2La6pDS6Q8ip9uUf80hNS7Zg49yZu9ekylv27V4THt5EkwLTXPblg-3D-3D&gt; 
- -- - - -- - - - -- - --------------- Email 9,712 ----------------------------
From: 
To: 
Date: 
xxxxxxxx 
xxxxxxxx 
07/16/2014 01:18 AM 
Subject: Save the Internet for the people 
To Chairman Tom Wheeler and the FCC Commissioners----
Chairman Wheeler, please keep the internet as it is today. The internet 
is the last part of my life that is not one sided in favor for the BIG 
businesses. They are the ones who hold our internet lives in their 
hands, but their overwhelming greed, they want, with your help and 
blessing, to squeeze the last dollar out of the rest of the population. 
Just what is the reason you are in f avor to make the change? 
of the very rich that want it, the rest of the country do not? 
seems you must side with the very rich? Is that it? 
There a few 
So it 
I was in the telephone industry when Judge Green handed down his verdict 
to level the playing field and allow competition to prevail. The price 

of telephone service dropped significantly, service greatly improved, and 
features and capabilities exploded. Now look what has happened, the 
telephone industry is coming back to where it was before the breakup of 
AT&amp;T. 
It is looking that, with your help, that the internet is going the same 
way, a few lording it over all the rest. What will be coming if this 
passes, is the AT&amp;T monopoly will coming back in the form of the 
internet. Look forward and you will see the damage this will do. It 
cannot improve the internet except in the pocket of a few. Is there any 
way to stop, or at least slow down the oligarchy? 
Jerry Sharp 
78633 
Email 9,7~3 
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:18 AM 
Subject: Docket number: 14-28 protecting an open internet 
To Chairman Tom Wheeler and the FCC Commissioners----
Please keep net neutrality and an open internet. I have a Masters Degree 
in Computer Science from NYU Courant Institute and very clearly 
understand the technical aspects of this issue. 
Thank you for your attention, 
Dan Robinson 
Daniel and Joy ROBINSON 
10804 
--- ------- --------- --------- Email 9,714 -------- ------------ --------
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:18 AM 
Subject: Comment Re: WC Docket No. 14-28 
As an Internet user who believes strongly in the importance of a free and 
open Internet, I urge the FCC to reclassify broadband Internet access as 
a telecommunications service, and save Net Neutrality. 
In addition, the FCC should reject the proposed rules that would allow 
Internet service providers to divide· the Internet into fast lanes for 
wealthy corporations and slow lanes for the rest of us. 
Daniel Robinson 
Skyview Ln 

New Rochelle, NY 10804 
&lt;http: // list.credoaction.com/ wf / open?upn=CFwW2LiM8egNfpSWPK172vck1Jm5Gzqa 
Ow5Fuc04BSKUOe3b9dNI-2BY8LSC8IROkLcn7v6blefynby69jDY-
2FWhe8DkOktPYvmVPyz7fsD6Z7HoTGFEOJj SGJSnP1ESpilvkM4YLKsrXI8JkmnsPCz8jqdvy 
zXquQrBK-2BvqUAleme-2FK8DuUmIHKDJ40BWy8pkKBwOsSN1CuVcCbtOyTk5sIA-3D-3D&gt; 
---- ---- ------- ---- - -- ------Email 9,715 ---- -- ---- -- ----- -- ---- --- --
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:18 AM 
Subject: Chairman Wheeler's "Fast Lane" and "Slow Lane" 
Chairman Wheeler's outrageous proposal for "Fast Lane" explicitly 
endorses "Slow Lane" for the rest of us. 
"Slow Lane" unless We the People can afford "Fast Lane" for all of 
our Internet use. 
"Slow Lane" for public schools? 
"Slow Lane" for US, State &amp; Local 
"Slow Lane" for public libraries? 
"Slow Lane" for small businesses, 
Outrageous! 
Outrageous! 
Governments? Outrageous! 
Outrageous! 
such as Starbucks free WiFi? 
Dan Du Bois, Culver City, CA 90230 
Retired Systems Administrator for California State University 
---- --- ---- - -- - - --- ----- - --- Email 9,716 ----- -- ---- - -------- - -------
From: xxxxxxxx 
To: xxxxxxxx 
Date: 07/16/2014 01:18 AM 
Subject: Comment Re: WC Docket No. 14-28 
As an Internet user who believes strongl y in the importance of a free and 
open Internet, I urge the FCC to reclassify broadband Internet access as 
a telecommunications service, and save Net Neutrality. 
In addition, the FCC should reject the proposed rules that would allow 
Internet service providers to divide the Internet into fast lanes for 
wealthy corporations and slow lanes for the rest of us. 
Lisa Pangborn 
6424 N. Newgard 
Chicago, IL 60626 
&lt;http://list.credoaction.com/wf/open?upn=CFwW2LiM8egNfpSWPK172vcklJm5Gzqa 
Ow5Fuc04BSI-2Bo-2FGMwyovOCkjrgsCUS1E6rpbe-2Fjlezjp-
2BJpvQmOuY3K7BVn9kPzb39v2tXQ6mghhsKgsAo- 2FykBIDM3jQ2k1Ele9s-
2BQNorsEfiszrWFhiTaJ09U4c78lsQKh4nCaJLMmGEJZEmxc-
2FsflqMTUOj 2BvocuemL32Y01-2F4HNm5-2FZtBA-3D-3D&gt; 

</str></arr>
  <arr name="viewingStatus"><str>Unrestricted</str></arr>
 </doc>
